(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
新衣装お披露目＆超告知あり!?
[New Outfit Reveal & Super Announcement!?]
痛くて目を塞いでも聞こえちゃう不安ショー
Even if I cover my eyes because it hurts, I still hear this uneasy show
悩んでも変わらないからなんだかんだやるしかないか
Worrying won't change anything, so in the end, I just have to do it
壊れるならいっそ直しやすいように
If it's going to break, I'd rather it be easy to fix
どんな形目指せるかな
I wonder what kind of shape I can aim for
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump with no running start, a dive with no safety line
今日のあたし褒めてあげたいじゃんか
I want to praise myself for today, don't I?
息したい もっと響きたい
I want to breathe, I want to resonate more
ねえあたし以上が見れるかも 妄想止まんないや
Hey, maybe I can see beyond myself, my delusions won't stop
ファッションビート嗅いでみちゃう？
Want to get a taste of the Fashion Beat?
夢にアッソなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just say 'whatever' to my dreams
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I be the one to make it come true, or will I leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just want to win against myself
ニューファッションビート愛を喰らう
New Fashion Beat, consuming love
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I refuse to lose, it leaves a tasteless feeling
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolving and turning to ashes time and again, the personification of a reborn bug
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない
I won't let myself rot just yet, no, not yet
チクチク刺してくるのは飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of the constant pricking
ごめん鬱雑い言葉遊びはどうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, but please keep those annoying wordplays tucked away
あたしこそがライバル 当たり前の解釈
I am my own rival, that's only natural
どうしたらいい わかってるのに
Even though I already know what I need to do
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump with no running start, a dive with no safety line
今日のあたし出来る気しないなって<
Thinking 'I don't feel like I can do it today'
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
But isn't it impossible not to care?
ねえあたし以外と比べてもクソつまんないじゃんか
Hey, comparing me to anyone else is just super boring, isn't it?
うぜーー
So annoying!
ファッションビート嗅いでみちゃう？
Want to get a taste of the Fashion Beat?
夢にアッソなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just say 'whatever' to my dreams
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I be the one to make it come true, or will I leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just want to win against myself
ニューファッションビート愛を喰らう
New Fashion Beat, consuming love
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I refuse to lose, it leaves a tasteless feeling
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolving and turning to ashes time and again, the personification of a reborn bug
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない 止まれない
I won't let myself rot just yet, no, not yet, I can't stop
誰かじゃないあたし自身だ 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
It's not anyone else, it's me! The personification of a reborn bug
まだまだ散ってあげない そう、ない
I won't scatter just yet, no, not yet
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat!
ファッションビート！
DAIDAIDAIファンタジスタ
[Song: DAIDAIDAI Fantasista]
Nya! Hello!!
The beautiful days!
割目しちゃってくれ！
Keep your eyes glued on me!
Please call 'Elite'!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
さぁ、待ったはなしだ！
Now, no more waiting!
始めちゃえ！
Let's get started!
今日も気合を溜めて
Today too, building up my energy...
いざ挑戦だ
...here goes the challenge!
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしてないで<
Hesitation is forbidden, don't just tap your feet!
一緒に「せのっ！」で
Together on "Ready, set..."
もっと前にいこう
...let's step forward even more.
ね？
Right?
さぁ、なんとかなっちゃえ！
Come on, it'll work out somehow!
飛び込んで
Let's dive in!
なんたってじっとしてたって も人生は冒険だ
After all, even if we stand still, life is an adventure!
こんがらがったら またわかんないぞ
If things get tangled up, we'll lose our way again...
道のりは
...our path is...
困難だ！なんなんだ！衝動だ！
...difficult! What is it! An impulse!
ダダダダ（あっぽ）
Da-da-da-da (Ah-ho!)
メソメソしちゃって 気持ちに負けちゃって
Whining and crying, yielding to your feelings...
あれ？一体全体どうしたん？
Wait? What on earth happened?
絶対絶命
Absolute desperation!
君たちには
For you all...
涙は似合わないね！
...tears don't suit you, right!
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 冒険に 飛び出そうぜ！
Da-da-da-da! Let's jump into the adventure!
いいじゃんっ！
It's fine!
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 心配も 重ねて
Da-da-da-da! Accumulating worries too...
成長
...and growing!
してっ！
Do it!
Happy feel so で
Feeling so happy,
君と笑い話にしよう
let's laugh about it with you!
（うぇい）
(Way!)
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 問題も 吹き飛ばせ！
Da-da-da-da! Blow away the problems too!
いつか
Someday...
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 到達の 素敵な 結末
Da-da-da-da! Reaching a wonderful end...
Please me!!
さぁ、付いてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の New world
Forward! To an unprecedented new world
(Let's go!!)
あながち間違ってる？ また墓穴掘ってる？
Am I totally wrong? Digging my own grave again?
勉強！ 勉強！
Study! Study!
はいはいはい、知ってます。 待って、なんか違ってる！
Yes yes yes, I know. Wait, something is wrong!
ぶっちゃけ 有識者の皆様に 感謝してます
Honestly, I'm grateful to all the experts out there.
Nice comment 待ってんぜ （あ～ね）
Waiting for your nice comments. (Ah, I see!)
ウジウジしちゃって 心にロックしちゃって
Fretting and locking up your heart...
ほら だんだんだんだん ダウンしちゃって
Look, you're slowly getting down!
絶対
Absolute...
絶命
...desperation!
君たちには
For you all...
笑顔が足りないね！
there's not enough smiles!
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 好きじゃ 済まさない！
Da-da-da-da-da! 'Just liking' won't cut it!
いいじゃんっ！
It's fine!
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 満足の その上の 感動を
Da-da-da-da! The deep emotion beyond mere satisfaction...
もっと欲しがっちゃって？
Do you want even more of it?
豪快に
Splendidly,
贅沢にいこう
let's go extravagantly!
（うぇい）
(Way!)
全然全然ないなんて 凹んじゃったって
Even if you get depressed saying 'there's none at all'...
ならば
Then...
全身全霊 エンジン
with your whole heart and soul, engine...
マジの
real...
全開で！
at full throttle!
Nya! Hello!!
さぁ beautiful に 意気込んで
Come on, enthusiastically and beautifully...
進め！
forward!
Freedom way!
(wow wow) 乗り遅れんなよみんな
(wow wow) Don't miss the ride, everyone!
(wow wow) 声を聞かせてくれ！ Yeah!
(wow wow) Let me hear your voice! Yeah!
(wow wow) 歌おう 声高らかに
(wow wow) Let's sing out loud!
(wow wow) ベイベー ベイベー なんていうか
(wow wow) Baby baby, how should I say it...
あぁ、なんだかちょっと 言い表せない
Ah, somehow I can't quite describe it
一人ぼっちで 見てた光景を<
The scenery I used to look at all alone...
今はきっと あなたと冒険してる！
now I am surely adventuring through with you!
ダダダダダ...
Da-da-da-da-da...
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 好きじゃ 収まらない！
Da-da-da-da-da! 'Just liking' isn't enough!
だから
So...
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 最高レベルに
Da-da-da-da! To the highest level,
ガチの
at our absolute...
全開で！
full throttle!
Nya! Hello!!
さぁ 踊りゃうぜ！
Come on, let's dance!
ずっと大冒険しよう Yeah!!
Let's keep on this grand adventure forever, Yeah!
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 問題も 吹き飛ばせ！
Da-da-da-da! Blow away the problems too!
いつか
Someday...
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ 到達の 素敵な 結末
Da-da-da-da! Reaching a wonderful end...
Please me!!
さぁ、付いてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の New world
Forward! To an unprecedented new world
カツモクしちゃってくれ！
Keep your eyes glued on me!
Please call 'Elite'!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
とくべチュ、して
[Song: TokuBeChu, shite]
「とくべチュ、して？」
Would you do a "special chu"?
Oh baby「I love you」じゃ足りない！
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough!
一番大事がいい
I want to be your number one most important person!
君が作るオリジナルの
The original that you create...
特別チューして。
...give me a special "chu".
まぶしくって 目がさめて (Oh yeah!)
My eyes open, blindingly bright (Oh yeah!)
愛おしく思ってるよ (Oh yeah!)
I'm thinking of you, feeling so dear (Oh yeah!)
眠り姫のように
Like a sleeping beauty
優しく口づけして
Kiss me gently
ゴミめいた この世界 (Oh yeah!)
This world, it feels like trash (Oh yeah!)
ピュアがかる 君がいる (Oh yeah!)
Pure you are here (Oh yeah!)
すべてに触れずに
Without touching anything
2人だけでいよう
Let's just be the two of us
私のこと 独占して
Monopolize me
君だけのモノに なってもいい
It's okay to make me yours
なんでも ある日の「なんでもない」
Any day, an ordinary "nothing special"
気付いてね
Notice it, okay?
Oh baby, I love you じゃ足りない
Oh baby, I love you isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special"
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss
Hey, give me more, give me a kiss
もう私は君でいっぱいだよ
I'm already full of you
ほどけない リボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie it tight with our pinky fingers
そうよ 一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want us to be together forever
とくべちゅが欲しい
I want to be special
2人きり週末は (Oh yeah!)
Just the two of us this weekend (Oh yeah!)
奏でてよ ハーモニー (Oh yeah!)
Play me a harmony (Oh yeah!)
流れ星見たら
When you see a shooting star
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me
あまあまな君なのに (Oh yeah!)
Even though you're sweet and soft (Oh yeah!)
広い街 吸い込まれ (Oh yeah!)
Sucked into the wide city (Oh yeah!)
戦う姿に
Your fighting figure
大きいはなまるだね
Is a big "well done" (hanamaru)
好きなとこ、優しいとこ。
Where I like you, where you're kind.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ
Where I dislike you, where you're kind too
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone
私だけ 独り占め
I'll keep you all to myself
う～だって 今までの人と
Ugh, because with others up to now
同じはいらないんです
I don't need the same thing
ねぇ もっと Give me more love
Hey, give me more, give me more love
私のために 生きてほしいんです
I want you to live for my sake
だから ウサギと私は
So, the rabbit and I
寂しくさせないで
Won't let you be lonely
そんなんじゃ 束縛じゃないわ
That's not what I call being possessive
苦しいのが好き
I like the pain
ショートケーキ
Shortcake
イチゴみたいに座ってもいい？
Is it okay if I sit like a strawberry?
赤く甘い 恋だもん
It's a red, sweet love
誰かにあげた 「大好き」も
"I love you"s you gave to others
返してもらって 全部私に
Get them back and give them all to me
ちょうだい もっと！
Give it to me, more!
君は 神様が作る
You are a person created by God
奇跡のようなヒト
A miracle-like human
すねた顔も その寝顔も
Your sulking face, your sleeping face too
守ってあげるね (Yeah!)
I'll protect them all (Yeah!)
Oh baby, I love you じゃ足りない
Oh baby, I love you isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special"
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss
Hey, give me more, give me a kiss
もう私は君でいっぱいだよ
I'm already full of you
ほどけない リボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie it tight with our pinky fingers
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, my first and last
とくべちゅにしてね
make me your special, okay?
はーい、みんなー、はろー！
Hi, everyone, hello!
エリートみこアイドルのさくらみこー！
It's elite shrine maiden idol Sakura Miko!
さくらみこ生誕祭2026「Fashion Beat」に来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you so much for coming to Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026 'Fashion Beat'! Yay!
今年でなんとみこちゃん、18.8歳になりました！
And this year, Miko-chan has actually turned 18.8 years old!
たぶん18.8歳だよね？
It's probably 18.8, right?
はい、あの0.1でね、刻んでいく系のVTuberですから。
Yes, because I'm the type of VTuber who ages in increments of 0.1.
今年でもう18.8歳になっております！わー！
So I've reached 18.8 years old this year! Wow!
えー、そしてそして、今回のライブのテーマは、Fashion Beatにちなんでいるんですね。ファッションとなっております。
And, and, the theme of this live show is based on 'Fashion Beat'. It's all about 'Fashion'.
色んなね、演出が盛りだくさんなので、ぜひ楽しんでください！
There are lots of different special performances, so please enjoy!
じゃあね、ちょっと、もうファッションちゅうので、みこちゃんも、ちょっとだけチェンジしちゃおうかなー。
Well then, since it's about fashion, maybe Miko-chan should change a little bit too.
はい、上向いててください。よいしょ。
Okay, look up, please. Up we go.
はい、じゃーん！
And, ta-da!
ということで、えー、クリスマスのね、ライブではね、あの、あまりひ...
So, for the Christmas live, I couldn't really...
紹介をしなかった
The one I didn't introduce earlier...
こちらの、えー、キャストオフバージョンになっております！
This is actually the cast-off version of it!
こんな感じになってます！可愛いでしょう？
It looks like this! Isn't it cute?
ちょっとセクシーですけどね。
Though it's a bit sexy.
はい～
Yes~
かわいい！
So cute!
はい、次の曲はこれで披露しようと思っております！
And yes, I'm planning to perform the next song in this!
そして、先ほどね、２曲ね、お送りしましたが、どうでしたか？
Also, I performed two songs earlier, how did you like them?
みこのオリ曲の『だいだだいファンタジスタ』と、
My original song 'Dai Dai Dai Fantasista'...
そして、イコラブさんの『部活中』を、
...and Equal Love's 'Bukatsuchuu'!
披露させていただきました！
I'm so glad I got to perform them!
とっても可愛かったでしょう？
Weren't they super cute?
きゅるん、きゅるん、はい！
Squeak, squeak! Yes!
あ、そうだ！ステージもね、ちょっと見せたいんですけど、
Oh, that's right! I also want to show you the stage,
見てください！
take a look!
こちら、今回のテーマにちなんで、作っていただきました！
We had this custom made based on this live show's theme!
ドレッサーとかね、めちゃくちゃね、なんってみこが、こう、小人になったみたいな感じなんですけど。
The dresser and everything is so huge, it feels like Miko shrank into a dwarf!
ね、とっても可愛くなっております！
See? It looks incredibly cute!
そしてこちらのトルソーに、みこちゃん、歴代の衣装とかも少し飾ってあります！
And on these dress forms, we have Miko's past outfits on display!
全部じゃないんですけどね。
Well, not all of them, though.
はい！
Yes!
えー、そして、最後にですね、
And finally...
たくさんの告知があったりとか、新衣装お披露目もございますので、
we have lots of announcements and a new outfit reveal too!
ぜひ、楽しんでいただけたらなと思っております！
So I hope you'll look forward to it all!
では！
Now then!
早速ゲストパート行こうと思いますよ！
Let's move right into the guest segment!
よいしょ、こうして、
Alright, like this...
それでは、この後も楽しんでね！
Everyone, please enjoy the rest of the show!
よし！
Let's go!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
おもしろいって言いたいのに
Don't you think it's boring when you wanna say it's interesting,
言えないなんてつまらないでしょ
but you can't?
おなじになっていい子でなんて保存
I don't wanna be the same and be a good girl,
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ
I'm sure you don't either.
だれかのルールに
I don't want to be bound...
しばられたくはないの
...by someone else's rules.
わがまま ドキドキ
I'm so selfish, my heart is pounding...
このままでいたい
...I want to stay the way I am.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
このせまいこころの
I want to break the narrow...
檻もこわして自由になりたいの
...cage of my heart and be free!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
感覚を研ぎ澄ませてキミのように
I can sharpen up my senses, like you,
すいこまれてく螺旋模様みたいに
sucking it all in so it looks like a spiral...
I wanna be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
ただふつうに生きたいのに
I just want to live my life normally...
変なことってつまらないでしょ
...isn't it boring to say that I'm weird?
きめつけないでいい子でなんて
Don't judge me, I don't wanna be a good girl,
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ保存
I'm sure you don't either.
だれかのルールに しばられたくはないの
I don't want to be bound by anyone's rules.
わがまま
Selfish...
ドキドキ
...heart-pounding,
このままでいたい
I want to stay just like this.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
鉄の首飾りをはずして
Take off this iron collar,
ただ自由にいきたいだけ
I just want to live freely.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
このせまい こころの檻も
I want to break down this narrow prison of my heart
こわして自由になりたいの
and become free.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
咲き誇れ花よ舞い踊れ
Bloom in full glory, flowers, and dance!
明日を虹色に染め上げて
Coloring tomorrow in rainbow hues.
いくぞー！
Let's go!
今から歌うは
Now, the song we'll sing is...
ウルトラ スーパー
...an ultra-super...
いといとおかしの 夢色リズム
...very delightful dream-colored rhythm!
「おかし」なゆえにね 心惹かれるの
Because it's "strange/sweet", my heart is drawn to it.
まぁそんな話は とってもいいの
Well, that kind of talk is totally fine.
大事なのは 楽しむ心
The important thing is a heart that enjoys itself.
準備はいいかな？ 遅れないでよね
Are you ready? Don't be late!
あ！
Ah!
少しの勇気心に
With a little courage in our hearts...
靴紐結んで
...tie your shoelaces...
３・２・１で飛び出すの！
...and leap out on 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの ドキドキしたくない？
I want to be excited. Don't you want to feel your heart pound?
ウキウキさせてよ もういい？
Make me feel thrilled! Are you ready yet?
いやいやまだまだ！
No, no, not yet!
なんていうか終わらない
Somehow it won't end...
なんていうか止まらない
...somehow it won't stop!
まだまだ明日の景色を見ていたくない？
Don't you want to keep looking at tomorrow's scenery?
咲き誇れ！
Bloom in full glory!
だからここは 最高のフェスティバル
That's why this is the greatest festival!
お祭りリズムで ノリノリ
Getting into the groove with the festival rhythm...
笑顔満開→無限大
...smiles in full bloom to infinity!
It's Alright!
舞い踊れ！手を取り合って 跳びはねて
Dance! Hold hands and leap!
君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Tell me your color, the color that piques my curiosity!
そんな感じで 夢のビート聴かせてよ
Just like that, let me hear the dream beat!
続けて歌うは
Continuing on, we'll sing...
ウルトラ スーパー
...an ultra-super...
いといとおかしの 夢色リズム
...very delightful dream-colored rhythm!
もしかしましても さっきも言ったっけ？
Or wait, did I already say that?
まぁそんな話は とってもいいの
Well, that kind of talk is totally fine.
大事なのは 信じる心
The important thing is a believing heart.
君だけ聞こえる リズムに任せて
Leave it to the rhythm that only you can hear.
あ！
Ah!
星空きらめく街を
The city shining under the starry sky...
もっともっと照らしたい
...we want to light it up more and more!
３・２・１で飛び出すの！
Leap out on 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの ドキドキしたくない？
I want to be excited. Don't you want to feel your heart pound?
ウキウキさせてよ もういい？
Make me feel thrilled! Are you ready yet?
いやいやまだまだ！
No, no, not yet!
なんていうか終わらない
Somehow it won't end...
なんていうか止まらない
...somehow it won't stop!
今宵も夢色を抱きしめて
Let's embrace the dream color tonight as well.
いっくぞー！
Let's go!
咲き誇れ！
Bloom in full glory!
だからここは 最高のフェスティバル
That's why this is the greatest festival!
愛色のリズムに ドキドキさ
Pounding to the indigo rhythm...
空に満開→無限大
...full bloom in the sky to infinity!
It's Alright!
舞い踊れ！手を取り合って 跳びはねて
Dance! Hold hands and leap!
君色教えて 内緒にするね color
Tell me your color, I'll keep it a secret!
そんな感じで
Just like that...
夢のビートきざもうよ
Let's keep the beat of our dreams going!
さわげー！
Make some noise!
咲き誇れ！
Bloom in full glory!
だから22日のフェスティバル
So here is our 22nd festival!
常熱リズムでノリノリたいよ
I want to groove with this passionate rhythm!
笑顔満開 → 無限大 It's Alright!
Smiling faces in full bloom to infinity, It's Alright!
ひいふうみいて 編み上げて
One, two, three, let's braid it up!
君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Tell me your color, I'm curious about it!
そんな感じで！ 夢のビート聴かせてよ
Just like that! Let me hear the beat of your dreams!
だから止まらない！
So we won't ever stop!
はっ！ はっ！
Ha! Ha!
ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya!
はー どっこい！
Ha- dokkoi!
どっこいしょ！ どっこいしょ！
Dokkoisho! Dokkoisho!
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
ぶつけたところから
From the place where it was bruised...
熟れていく果実のように
...ripening like a fruit.
僕らは些細なことでへこたれたよな
We got discouraged by trivial things, didn't we?
かさぶたになれずに
Without ever becoming a scab...
息せき切ってがむしゃらに
Breathing hard and recklessly,
輝く一等星をめがけて
aiming for the shining first-magnitude star,
手を伸ばしたよな
we reached out our hands, didn't we?
繊細されど大胆だ
Delicate, yet bold,
うるさい これが切り札だ
Shut up, this is our trump card!
泣き虫されど熱血だ
A crybaby, yet hot-blooded,
うるさい これが持ち味だ
Shut up, this is our specialty!
未開拓冒険地帯
An unexplored adventure zone,
好奇心旺盛時代
an era of thriving curiosity!
何が綺麗かは分かる
We know what is beautiful,
見る目ならばある
we have an eye for it!
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is being serious ridiculous?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We are doing our absolute best!
振りかざせ存在を
Brandish your existence!
掻き乱せ心臓を
Stir up your heart!
あとどれくらい続いていくだろう
How much longer will this continue?
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we protected to the end...
何よりもの贅沢だ
...is the greatest luxury of all!
きっといつか焦がれ思い返す
Surely someday we will yearn for it and look back,
名前のない関係を
on this relationship with no name,
捨てきれない感情を
on these feelings we can't throw away.
何気ない今日を忘れないでね
Please don't forget this casual today.
悩んでた種の色が
The color of the seed I worried over...
昨日とはまるで違うとか
...is completely different from yesterday,
そんなの日常茶飯事で
things like that happen every single day,
心は素直のようだ
yet our hearts seem to be honest.
戦友だとか親友は
Whether we are comrades-in-arms or best friends,
うるさい どれも正解だ
Shut up, any of those is correct!
初恋だとか失恋は
Whether it's first love or a broken heart,
うるさい どれも宝石だ
Shut up, each one of them is a gem!
天才的 人生企画
Genius-level life planning,
問題集 対抗美学
a collection of problems, a rival aesthetic.
君はなにをしてんのかな
I wonder what you are doing right now,
話がしたい
I want to talk with you.
風に乗って青春が
Riding on the wind, our youth
この想いを運んだ
carried these feelings along.
僕ら全力も超えたいんだ
We want to surpass even our absolute best!
立ちすくむ同士だって
Even if we are comrades frozen in place,
引き連れていこうぜ
let's bring them along with us!
この上ない今日を 過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend this peerless today with you!
今しかできないことがある
There are things we can only do right now,
今しかできない恋がある
there is a love we can only experience now.
今しかできないから 僕らに託された時間が惜しい
Because we can only do it now, the time entrusted to us is so precious.
今しか見られない君の笑顔も
Your smile, which can only be seen now,
君の涙も
your tears,
君の全ても
everything about you,
大人びていく
is starting to look grown-up.
有限だから最高だ
Because it's finite, it's the absolute best!
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is being serious ridiculous?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We are doing our absolute best!
振りかざせ存在を
Brandish your existence!
掻き乱せ心臓を
Stir up your heart!
胸に刻めば続いていくのだろう
If you carve it into your chest, it will surely continue.
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we protected to the end
何よりも贅沢だ
is the greatest luxury of all.
きっといつか焦がれ思い返す
Surely, someday we will yearn and look back on this.
名前のない関係を
This nameless relationship,
捨てきれない感情を
these emotions we can't throw away,
何気ない今日も忘れないでね
please don't forget even this ordinary day.
この上ない今日を忘れないでね
Please don't forget this peerless today.
アイ！アイドルだから
Ah! Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself!
君と夢見るんだ
I'm dreaming together with you,
不器用でもいいか
is it okay even if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom in full glory!
初のイベント
Our first event,
重要なしデフォ
was naturally of no importance.
そんな私が夢を見ました決まり
A girl like that had a dream:
アイドルという生き方
The lifestyle of an idol,
憧れて
that's what I yearned for.
無敵エリート
"Invincible elite"!
笑顔はチート
"A smile that is a cheat code"!
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who are watching someone like me,
好きなとこはどこですか？
which part of me do you like?
わがままを許して
Please forgive my selfishness.
ステージ経験値 涙にじんんで
Stage experience points, blurred by tears,
それでも絶対負けたくない
even so, I absolutely don't want to lose!
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Carrying my message on the cherry blossoms, let it reach you,
愛で溢れますように
so that it may overflow with love!
アイ！アイドルだから
Ah! Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself!
君と夢見るんだ
I'm dreaming together with you,
不器用でもいいか
is it okay even if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
空想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a fantasy.
私らしく桜色ね
In my own cherry blossom color!
磨いたスキル
My polished skills,
実力発揮
showing my true ability,
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
the days I can enjoy have been increasing!
アイドルとして生きてる
I am living as an idol
君のおかげ
all thanks to you!
アホ毛はキュート
My cowlick is cute,
勝ち確ルート
a guaranteed path to victory!
そんな私についてきてよね！
So please follow me!
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy side is forgiven,
最強じゃん！
isn't that the absolute best?!
痛いの痛いのグッと飲み込んで
Gulping down all the pain,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to multiply smiles with my own smile.
桜前線が君の町に
Let the cherry blossom front head to your town
春を届けるように
to bring the spring to you!
アイ！アイドルだけは
Ah! Only the identity of an idol
譲りたくないんだ
is something I will never give up!
君に魅せたいんだ
I want to enchant you,
理想超え挑むのよ
exceeding ideals to challenge myself.
駆け抜けろ
Run right through,
最高景色見せたる
I will show you the greatest view!
信じていいよ 桜を
You can believe in the cherry blossoms.
さあ皆で咲かそう 満開のピンクで世界染めて
Come on, let's all bloom and dye the world in full pink!
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears...
あぁ、この涙はね
Ah, these tears are...
悲しい方じゃないから
...not because I'm sad,
安心して
so don't worry.
きれいだね
They're beautiful.
今年も誕生日をお祝いしてくれてありがとう
Thank you for celebrating my birthday with me again this year!
みんな大好きだよ
I love you all so much!
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep on challenging myself.
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it wrong to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
幸福だけじゃ終わらない世界
In a world that doesn't end with just happiness,
私らしく
in my own way,
さくら色ね
cherry blossom pink!
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ありがとうね！
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ありがとう！ちゅっ！
Thank you! *muah*!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
お祝いしてくれてありがとうね！楽しんでるー？
Thank you for celebrating with me! Are you enjoying yourselves?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう！んー、ちゅ！
Thank you! Mm, *muah*!
見てるよ！みんな見てるよー！
I see you! I can see everyone!
ということで！ライブ、まだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますかー？
And with that! Are you ready to get even more hyped for the live show?
みんな！まだまだ見逃さないでね！
Everyone! Don't miss a single moment yet!
よし、次の曲いきます！
Alright, let's move on to the next song!
Now I'm ready, I'm ready to go
花が咲く時が来たんだ
The time for the flower to bloom has come
Are you ready? わかるでしょ
Are you ready? You know it, right?
やってみせる Make it through
I'll show you I can make it through
ほら ほら ほら
Look, look, look,
ソワソワしてきた？
are you starting to feel restless?
時は過ぎちゃうから 今すぐにさ
Because time is passing by, right now,
Let's work it out
もう目を背けやしないんだ
I won't look away anymore
自分で Make it better
I'll make it better myself
作る正解を
Creating the right answer
I just wanna, just wanna find somebody
私よりも強気な
who is even more confident than me,
ダレカ
someone...
夢中になる Make you hot
Captivated, make you hot
準備体操お済みですか？
Are you done with your warm-up exercises?
Victory
So now let's start the war!
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay
The dream of the future, ay-ay,
信じて進むだけ
I'll just believe and move forward.
誰にも絶対
I absolutely won't
負ける気なんかない
feel like losing to anyone!
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond!
恋に踊れ
Dance in love,
情熱全て
with all your passion!
もっと先を知りたい もう止まらない Ay-ay
I want to know what's further ahead, I won't stop anymore, ay-ay!
I will lead the way
Just come along my way
Hey!
Don't kill my vibe
行こう 一番上まで
Let's go all the way to the very top!
ちょっと待ってよなんか
Wait a minute, if it's
誤解なら困っちゃうな
some kind of misunderstanding, that'd be trouble.
ねえ
Hey,
蹴落とすため戦う訳ではないの
I'm not fighting to kick others down.
Just wanna keep challenging myself
こんな fantasy ハマったら
Once you fall for this kind of fantasy,
もっともっと 欲しくなっちゃうよ
you'll want more and more!
もう何も恐れはしないんだ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore,
君となら行ける気がするから
because I feel like I can go if I'm with you.
Come join us
ほら今聞こえてくるから
Look, I can hear it now,
Yea, 私の名を呼ぶ方へ
yeah, coming from where they call my name!
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay
The dream of the future, ay-ay,
信じて進むだけ
I'll just believe and move forward.
誰にも絶対
I absolutely won't
負ける気なんかない
feel like losing to anyone!
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond!
雨を受け 夜を抜け
Taking the rain, breaking through the night,
青空の光 求めた
I searched for the light of the blue sky.
Ah whoa
一つも無駄はないさ
Not a single thing is wasted,
パワーに変えて 輝いてくから
because I'll turn it into power and shine!
KIRA KIRA 雫弾けた
Sparkling droplets burst,
Ah 神の思し召しだ
ah, it's God's will!
連れてくよ Make you high
I'll take you, make you high
後悔はさせませんわ
I won't let you regret it!
超えるんだ boundary
I'll cross the boundary,
So now let's start the war!
I'm fighting with myself
負けなんてない Ay-ay
There is no such thing as defeat, ay-ay,
勝負受けて立つだけ
I'll just accept the challenge and stand tall.
もう自分以外
There is no one else
私に勝てない
who can beat me besides myself!
君がいれば何度も立ち上がるわ
If you are here, I'll rise up again and again!
愛を歌え
Sing of love,
想い全て
with all your feelings!
逃げたくはない 待てない
I don't want to run away, I can't wait
まだ終われない
I can't end yet
I need you to stay
You make me feel okay
Hey! It's time to shine
行こう空の上まで
Let's go up to the sky
Weh oh weh oh
Ram pam pam para pum pum pa
Ahhh ooh uh
唸るぜ
I'll roar
血泥ついたって
Even if covered in bloody mud
守りたい
I want to protect you
革命途中だって
Even in the middle of a revolution
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world where darkness seeps in
見つけた
I found it
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
A sweet, muddy look
変に色気あるから困った
It's troubling because you have a strange sexiness
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
Wanting to muster the courage to hold hands
身の程わきまえてちゃできないね
You can't do it if you know your place
暗いトンネルの壁
The wall of a dark tunnel
したたり落ちる悲鳴
Dripping screams
しめやかに高鳴る心
A solemnly throbbing heart
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no, wait, wait
呪いも病みも抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and the sickness
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if we run wild around here?
ああ
Ah
唸るぜ
I'll roar
血泥ついたって
Even if covered in bloody mud
守りたい
I want to protect you
革命途中だって
Even in the middle of a revolution
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world where darkness seeps in
見つけた
I found it
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no, wait, wait
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to be by your side, no matter what
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I end up expecting things from clumsy you too
しがみつけば消えそうな君に
To you who seems like you'll disappear if I cling
恋の爪立てて近づいてもいい？
Can I claw my way closer with love's claws??
身を任せて抱かれて
Entrusting myself to be held
全て失ってもいい
I don't mind losing everything
しめやかに高鳴る心
A solemnly throbbing heart
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no, wait, wait
呪いも病みも君となら
Even curses and sickness, if it's with you
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if we run wild around here??
ああ
Ah
泣けるぜ
I can cry
絶句しちゃうまで
Until I'm speechless
離れない
I won't let go
革命途中だって
Even in the middle of a revolution
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you
揺蕩う旅の狭間で
In the midst of a swaying journey
見つけた
I found it
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
突き進むなら二人で
If we forge ahead, let's do it together
革命途中だって夢に熱中
Even in the middle of a revolution, I'm passionate about my dreams
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no, wait, wait
呪いも病みも抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and the sickness
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
Is it okay if we run wild around here, right?
怖くたって
Even if I'm scared
唸るぜ
I'll roar
血泥ついたって
Even if covered in bloody mud
守りたい
I want to protect you
革命途中だって
Even in the middle of a revolution
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world where darkness seeps in
見つけた
I found it
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
飛べ 起こせ 願うは事故
Fly, wake it up! Wishing for an accident
一世一代 さあ何賭す？自問自答
Once in a lifetime, come on, what will you bet? Self-questioning
勝つか負けるか ドローなんてないわ
Win or lose, there's no such thing as a draw
幕開けるわ
The curtain opens
カッチンして ラッキーマニー どっちもむりー シガーシガー
Click it, lucky money, both are impossible... Cigar, cigar
引けるか否か のか 自分次第だ いだな
Can you pull it off or not? It's up to you.
余裕で！ 振り切り 全BETだぜい イェイイェイイェイ
With ease! Going all out, all bet, yeah!
そこどけ！ そう このエース かっさらうのは アタシだ
Out of the way! Yes, this ace, I'm the one who'll steal it!
Stay もういい 勝ったなら平常心
Stay, enough already, if you win, stay calm
ね プレイボーイ 行け Don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Hey playboy, go, don't get in my way, see ya, shut up!
ワンツースリー ワンツースリー ワンツースリー Sit down, Sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
ワンツースリー ワンツースリー ワンツースリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
はーもう フリーズキメてや 投げるのは賽？才？か匙か？
Ah, already frozen, what's thrown, dice, talent, or a spoon?
そんな小さい尺じゃはかれない
You can't measure it with such a small scale
でしょう♪ そうでしょう♪ セイ・グッド・バイゃ
Right? That's right, say goodbye!
あっち こっち そっち どっち？ Nothing, nothing やむやむ
Here, there, which one, which way? Nothing, nothing, sickly
遥なき道より 道なき道より 闇闇闇
A path with no distance, a path with no road, darkness, darkness, darkness
空回りしそう でも まだ止めないで
I feel like I'm going in circles, but don't stop yet
あーのまれそう 声々、それぞれに
Ah, I feel like I'm being swallowed, each voice...
Get one's way!
アンタはここまで
You're done here
後ろだけ見とけ
Just look behind you
カッチンして ラッキーマニー どっちもむりー シガーシガー
Click it, lucky money, both are impossible... Cigar, cigar
引けるか否か のか 自分次第だ いだな
Can you pull it off or not? It's up to you.
余裕で！ 振り切り 全BETだぜい イェイイェイイェイ
With ease! Going all out, all bet, yeah!
そこどけ！ そう このエース かっさらうのは アタシだ
Out of the way! Yes, this ace, I'm the one who'll steal it!
Stay もういい 勝ったなら平常心
Stay, enough already, if you win, stay calm
ね プレイボーイ 行け Don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Hey playboy, go, don't get in my way, see ya, shut up!
ワンツースリー ワンツースリー ワンツースリー Sit down, Sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
ワンツースリー ワンツースリー ワンツースリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
まさかの倍々
Unexpected double
ワンツースリー ワンツースリー ワンツースリー Sit down, Sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
特報！
[News: Special Bulletin!]
フルアニメーションMV
[News: Full Animation MV]
配信後プレミア公開！
[News: Premiering after the stream!]
MV公開に先駆けてー
[News: Ahead of the MV release...]
ARE YOU READY?
ファッションビート
[Song: Fashion Beat]
痛くて目を塞いでも聞こえちゃう不安ショー
Even if I close my eyes in pain, I can hear the anxiety show
悩んでも変わらないから なんだかんだやるしかないか
Even if I worry, it won't change, so in any case, I have no choice but to do it
壊れるならいっそ 直しやすいように
If it's going to break, it's easier to fix
どんな形目指せるかな
What kind of shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
Jump without a running start, dive without a cord
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
Shouldn't I praise myself for today?
息したい もっと響きたい
I want to breathe, I want to resonate more
ねえ あたし以上が見れるかも
Hey, maybe you can see something beyond myself...
妄想止まんな いや
My delusions won't stop
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Shall I sniff the fashion beat?
夢に あっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't spit out things like "it was in my dreams"
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Is it up to me to make it come true, or leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just want to win against myself
ニュー ファッションビート 愛を喰らう
I'll devour this new fashion beat love
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I'm sorry, I won't accept losing, it doesn't taste good
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
No matter how many times, evolution becomes ash, personification of a bug that transforms
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない
Still not rotten yet, yes, not yet
チクチク刺してくるのは 飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm already tired of the stinging comments
ごめん 鬱雑い言葉遊びは どうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, please keep those annoying word games properly put away
あたしこそがライバル 当たり前の解釈
I am the rival, the obvious interpretation
どうしたらいい わかってるのに
I know what to do, but...
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
Jump without a running start, dive without a cord
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
Shouldn't I praise myself for today?
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？ ねえ
Isn't it impossible not to care? Hey,
あたし以外と比べても クソつまんないじゃんか
even compared to anyone else, it's incredibly boring!
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Shall I sniff the fashion beat?
夢に...
In my dreams...
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't spit out 'whatever' in my dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is it myself who makes it come true?
それとも誰かにお任せか
Or is it left to someone else?
ただただ
Just...
自分に勝ちたい
I want to win against myself!
ニュー
New...
ファッションビート　愛を喰らう
...fashion beat, devouring love!
負けるなんてごめんだ
I won't accept losing...
味がしないな
...it's flavorless!
何度でも灰になる進化
An evolution that turns to ash time and again,
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
personification of a bug that is reborn.
まだまだ
Still, still,
腐ってあげない
I won't let it rot!
そう、ない
Yeah, no!
止まれない
I won't stop!
誰かじゃないあたし自身だ
It's not someone else, it's me myself!
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a bug that is reborn.
まだまだ
Still, still,
散ってあげない
I won't let it scatter!
そう、ない
Yeah, no!
みんなー、ライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for watching the live show!
これからは告知の時間です！
From here on, it's time for some announcements!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
さくらみこ誕生日記念2026、記念グッズです！
The Sakura Miko Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise!
まずは、1つ目！こちら！タダーン！
First up, item number one! Here it is! Ta-dah!
アクリルパネル！
Acrylic panel!
イラストレーターはおるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
The illustration was drawn specially by Orudan-sensei!
テーマは電脳世界のミコ！
The theme is "Cyberworld Miko"!
新衣装のミコを描き下ろしてもらいました！
She drew Miko in her new outfit!
オーロラ加工でキラキラのアクリルパネルとなっております！めっちゃ可愛い！
It's a glittering acrylic panel with an aurora finish! So cute!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
スマホスタンドフィギュアです！
A smartphone stand figure!
スマホが立てかけられるスタンド、そして新衣装のミコのフィギュア！
A stand where you can prop up your smartphone, and a figure of Miko in her new outfit!
メチャクチャ可愛くないですか？これ、たくさんこだわったのでね！
Isn't it super cute? I put a lot of care into this!
ぜひね、このスタンドにスマホを立てかけて、配信見てくれたら嬉しいです！
So I'd love it if you prop up your phone on this stand to watch my streams!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
ガジェットケース！
Gadget case!
新衣装にちなんで、ちょっとこういう、あまり出さないグッズも考えてみました！
Inspired by the new outfit, I thought of trying some merchandise we don't usually release!
ケーブルとかね、モバイルバッテリーなど、小物を収納できるケースとなっております。
It's a case where you can store small items like cables and mobile batteries.
ソフトな素材になっているよ！
It's made of soft material!
最後はこちら！ナイロンジャケット！
And finally, this! Nylon jacket!
新衣装をモチーフにしたナイロンジャケットとなっております！
It's a nylon jacket designed with the new outfit as a motif!
ちょっとカッコいい目のデザインなので、みんな一緒にお揃いになってくれたら嬉しいです！
It has a slightly cool design, so I'd be happy if we can match!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the bonus for purchasing the full set!
さくらみこ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、おるだん描き下ろしポストカードとなっております！
An Orudan-drawn postcard featuring Sakura Miko's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped printed message!
ちょっと数量限定にはなるんですが、みんな、お早めによろしくお願いします！
It's limited in quantity, so please grab yours early!
そして、通常版は、さくらみこ箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードとなっております。
And the regular version comes with a postcard featuring a foil-stamped printed signature and message.
みんな、ぜひね、たくさん手に入れてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
I'd be really happy if everyone gets their hands on lots of them! Please support me!
そして、告知二つ目はこちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと、さくらみこ、学研さんの参考書シリーズが発売決定になりました！
Unbelievably, Sakura Miko's reference book series from Gakken will be released!
ホロライブStudy Book、さくらみこでもわかるシリーズとなっております！
The "Hololive Study Book: Sakura Miko can understand too" series!
中学漢字＋語彙、中学数学、中学英単語、中学地理＋都道府県の4冊が発売決定です！
Four books will be released: Junior High Kanji & Vocabulary, Math, English Vocabulary, and Geography & Prefectures!
そして、初回限定の愛蔵版も発売予定となっております！
Additionally, a first-press limited collector's edition is planned for release!
4月下旬頃より予約開始なので、引き続き続報をチェックしてね！
Pre-orders will start around late April, so keep checking for further updates!
「みこでもわかる」シリーズ、みんな説得力があると思うよね？
"Miko can understand too" series! Everyone thinks it sounds convincing, right?
次！三つ目は、こちら！
Next! The third one is here!
さくらみこ×フレーベル館、初の絵本「みこぴーとおおきなさくらのき」が、本日より発売です！
Sakura Miko's first picture book with Froebel-kan, "Mikopy and the Big Cherry Blossom Tree," is on sale starting today!
もう買ってくれた人もいるかな？
Maybe some of you have already bought it?
いつも支えてくれているみこぴーを題材に、夢だった絵本を作ることができました！
I was able to create my dream picture book featuring Mikopy, who always supports me!
全国の書店やローソンさんで購入可能なので、ぜひぜひみんな手に取ってください。よろしくお願いします！がんばりました！
It's available at bookstores nationwide and Lawson, so please pick up a copy. Thank you so much! I worked hard!
続いては、こちらの大発表！
Up next is this major announcement!
四つ目は、こちら！
The fourth one is here!
さくらみこ、フィギュア化が決定しました！
Sakura Miko's figure adaptation has been officially decided!
おるだん先生監修にて、みこの夢だった等身大フィギュアがついに完成です！やったー！
Under Orudan-sensei's supervision, Miko's dream life-sized figure is finally complete! Yay!
スケールフィギュアも同時に予約販売が決まりました！
Pre-orders for the scale figure have also been decided at the same time!
明日、3月6日から予約開始です！
Pre-orders start tomorrow, March 6th!
エキスポのデザインココさんブースで展示されるので、みんな見に来てね！たくさん写真撮ってね！
It will be exhibited at the Design COCO booth at the EXPO, so please come see it and take lots of photos!
また、この等身大フィギュアも展示される...
Also, where this life-sized figure will be exhibited...
京都IP書店×さくらみこのポップアップショップも開催決定となりました！すごい！
The Kyoto IP Shoten x Sakura Miko Pop-Up Shop has been officially decided too! Incredible!
リニューアルオープンした京都 蔦屋 IP書店...
At the newly reopened Kyoto Tsutaya IP Shoten...
4月28日から開催でーす！
Starting from April 28th, it will be held!
オリジナルグッズの発売やノベルティのコラボも行われるので
Original goods will be on sale, and novelty collaborations will also be held,
皆さん、楽しみにしてください！
so everyone, please look forward to it!
盛りだくさんだー！
It's packed with things!
そして、まだございます！
And, there's still more!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
さくらみこ×HYTE コラボPCケース、発売決定！
The Sakura Miko x HYTE collab PC case release is decided!
キーキャップとデスクマットのセットもございます！
Keycap and deskmat sets are also available!
先行予約、リリースメール通知、詳細については、
For details on pre-orders, release, and email notifications,
hyte.co/miko を見てみてください！
please check out hyte.co/miko!
楽しみにしてみてね！
Please look forward to it!
そして、
And,
今年もさくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗さんのコラボが実施中です！
this year, the Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collab is also underway!
今年でなんと4回目です！ありがとうございます！
This is actually our 4th time! Thank you so much!
3月31日までなので、みんなぜひ食べに行ってください！
It's until March 31st, so everyone please go and eat!
続いて、
Next,
新曲「FASHIONBEAT」、本日0時よりリリースです！
My new song 'FASHIONBEAT' is released today from midnight!
MVはこのあとプレミア公開！みんな見てね！
The MV will premiere after this! Everyone, watch it!
とっても豪華なアニメMVとなっております！よろしくお願いします！
It is a very gorgeous animated MV! Please support it!
はい、そして、こちら！
Yes, and this!
明日から、ホロライブエキスポ&7th Fes. 開催でーす！
Starting tomorrow, Hololive Expo & 7th Fes are being held!
3日間の開催ですよ！すごい！
It's a three-day event! Amazing!
みこはですね、7th Fes.では、Day 2のステージ2に参加します！みんな見に来てね！
As for Miko, I'll be participating in Stage 2 of Day 2 for the 7th Fes! Everyone, come see me!
このあとは、メンバー限定の撮影会もあるので、みんなみこピーになってね！
After this, we have a member-only photo session, so everyone, please become a Mikopi!
ということで、告知がもりもりの森になりましたが、みんなついてこれたかな？
So, the announcements became a thick forest, but could everyone keep up?
みこ、これからも頑張るので、よろしくお願いします！
Miko will keep doing her best, so please support me!
誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！おつみこー！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday! Otsumiko!
痛くて目 を塞い でも
Painful even if I close my eyes
聞こえちゃう不安ショー
The anxiety show I can hear
悩んでも変わらない から
Since it won't change even if I worry
なんだかんだやるしかないか
I have no choice but to do it anyway
壊れるならいっそ直しやすい ように
If it's going to break, it's better to fix it easily
どんな形目指せるかな
What kind of shape can I aim for
助走なしのジャンプ紐 無しでダイブ
Jump without a run-up, dive without a rope
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたい じゃんか
I want to praise today's me
息したい もっと響きたい
I want to breathe, I want to echo more
ねえあたし 以上が見れるかも
Hey, I might be able to see more than myself
妄想止まんな
The delusion won't stop
いや
No
ファッションビート
Fashion beat
嗅い でみちゃう？
Wanna try smelling it?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしない な
I can't vomit saying 'Oh well' at my dreams
叶えるのはあたし自身 か
Is it me who makes it come true
それとも誰かに お任せか
Or do I leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分 に勝ちたい
I just want to beat myself
ニューファッションビート愛を
The new fashion beat's love...
喰らう
...I eat
負けるなんて ごめんだ
I'm sorry to lose
味がしないな
It doesn't taste good
何度でも灰になる進化
Evolving while turning to ash again and again
生まれ変わるバグの 擬人化
Personification of a bug that is reborn
まだまだ腐ってあげない
I won't rot yet
そう、ない
Yeah, I won't
チクチク刺してくるのは
Being pricked...
飽き飽きしてるわ
...is boring
ごめん鬱雑い言葉遊びは
Sorry, annoying wordplay
どうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Please keep it properly
あたしこそがライバル
I am my own rival
当たり前の解釈
A natural interpretation
助走なしのジャンプ
Jump without a run-up,
紐なしでダイブ
dive without a rope
今日のあたし
Today's me,
出来る気がしないなって
I feel like I can't do it
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible not to care?
ねえあたし以外と比べても
Hey, even if I compare myself to others
クソつまんないじゃんか
It's damn boring, isn't it?
うぜーー
Noisy
ファッションビート
Fashion beat
生誕LIVE 2026♡ 今年も祝ってくれてありがとうにぇ！
Birthday Live 2026♡ Thank you for celebrating with me again this year, nye!
これからもあきらめない心でアイドルがんばる!! - さくらみこ
I'll keep doing my best as an idol with a never-giving-up heart!! - Sakura Miko